ABHIJITH KM

DEVELOPER WEB





PROFILE

I am a Software Engineer with expertise in React development, having worked at NimbleXcel and AdroitMinds Software Labs, where I deployed applications and APIs on AWS and integrated themes into existing projects. Previously, I served as an Instructor at Government Engineering College Idukki (GECI), where I contributed to labs, software development, and website management, and also developed key software solutions as a Tradesman at GECI.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- ReactJS
- jQuery
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- PHP
- Laravel
- Codelgniter
- MySQL

EDUCATION

B. TECH IN IT

Government Engineering College Idukki

2014 - 2017

DIPLOMA IN IT

Govt. Polytechnic College, Purappuzha

2011 - 2014

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

NimbleXcel Software Pvt Ltd

2024 - Present

React development

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

AdroitMinds Software Labs

2023 - 2024

- Deployment of multiple applications and APIs on AWS infrastructure
- Proficient in React development
- Integration of new themes into existing applications

INSTRUCTOR GRADE II

Government Engineering College Idukki (GECI)

2021 - 2023

- Assistance in Labs
- Member in College Software Development Cell (SDC)
- Member in College Website committee

TRADESMAN

Government Engineering College Idukki (GECI)

2017 - 2020

- OPPAM Web portal for IDUKKI DISTRICT CO OPERATIVE BANK(IDCB).
- Attendance management software.
- · Hostel admission Software



PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

WEBSITE FOR KERALA GAZETTED OFFICER'S ASSOCIATION (KGOA)

Laravel & MySQL

2021 - 2022

- Website and Web portal to manage their organizational activities which Includes Membership, KGOA News, Events management, etc.
- Fully manageable roles based Web Application

FEEDBACK MANAGEMENT SOFTWARE FOR GEC IDUKKI

Laravel & MySQL

2019 - 2021

- Feedback management software for faculty evaluation by students.
- Developed under Software Development Cell (SDC) GECI.
- Generalized application for academic institution
- Beneficiaries can register and create feedbacks.

HOSTEL ADMISSION SOFTWARE FOR GEC IDUKKI

Codelgniter & MySQL

2019 - 2021

• Software for managing Hostel admission of students

ATTENDANCE MANAGEMENT SOFTWARE FOR GEC IDUKKI

Codelgniter & MySQL

2017 - 2020

• Timetable based attendance management software

OPPAM WEB PORTAL FOR IDUKKI DISTRICT CO - OPERATIVE BANK(IDCB)

PHP & MySQL

2017 - 2018

- OPPAM was a new scheme for Kudumbashree.
- Web portal to manage the information about all Kudumbashree units and their accounts

REFERENCE

PROF. REJIN R

Assistant Professor in IT,Govt.Engineering College Idukki +91 9496209049, rejin@gecidukki.ac.in